Hello everyone, this is Shimanto Shorkar
and today I will be diving into a
Simulink project focused on photovoltaic
cells. But before we start, let me
clarify that this won't be a typical
tutorial in this video. I'm going to work
on this project live. You will witness my
mistake, see me search for solution and
witness those corrections. The beauty of
this kind of approach is that
You will not learn only from my
success, but also from my mistakes
along the way. So let's dive right in.
So first of all let's take the look what
will we need in this project. First open
the Simulink, double click and the search
bar will appear
Here is where we will select all the
essential blocks for this project.
The blocks will need is the solar cell,
PS constant ramp, variable
resistor, P Simulink converter, Simulink,
PS converter, product, voltage
sensor, current sensor, XY graph
solver configuration.
Now let's discuss why we will
use converter blocks in Simulink.
Physical system don't directly connect to
Simulink blocks because they are usually
non directional like real physical
components. On the other hand Simulink.
Blocks require information about
directionality.
Converter blocks actually bridge this
gap. Yeah, PS Simulink
converter transform a physical signal
into a Simulink output signal, which
can then be connected to a Simulink
block. Conversely, A Simulink
PS converter transform A Simulink input
signal into a physical system ready to be
used in a  blocks.
Now let's get into a the wiring.
This blocks. The variable
resistor block connects the connects in
series with the solar cell blocks,
responding the ramp signal from the
input port via ramp block.
Note that we use Simulink PS converter
between the ramp block and the variable
resistor block because they belong to
separate libraries.
To measure the current and voltage of the
circuit, we add the current sensor in
series and the voltage sensor in parallel
to the variable resistor.
Because both the current and voltage
sensor are physical system, we use
PS Simulink converter to display their
result in the XY graph block.
To determine the overall power of the
solar cell, we use the product block. It
multiplies the voltage and current.
The output will result in two curves.
The first curve represents P
characteristic curve and the second curve
is the V-I characteristic curve.
After connecting all the blocks, if we
run the simulation it will compile and
show us the I-V curves.
As you can see, our PV curve is perfect,
but the IV curve isn't ideal.
Clearly I have made some mistakes
somewhere. The problem seems to
to be in the XY graph block. Yeah
initially I had trouble understanding
it so I I did some research and
found out that the first X is represent
the X axis and the second axis is the Y
axis.
I correct the correction but if you
didn't go well so
I also after some investigation I
checked the solar cell block and found
that the short circuit current is
7.34 MPR and the open circuit
current is 0.6 . VoltI
adjusted the XY block accordingly
for the IV curve. The X axis
range from zero to
0.7 as voltage. Voltage
is on the X axis. With the
maximum voltage of 0.6 Volt. That
way axis goes 4 zero to 8
as current is on the X axis
while current on the Y axis and the
maximum current value is 7.34
MPR. I also made adjustment on
the P-V blocks setting. The X axis
ranges from zero to 0.77
Voltvoltage and the
Y axis from zero to 4 representing the
power. With these
changes then we will run the simulation
and we'll see that our curves are now
perfect.
OK, you can find the symbolic file in my
GitHub repository and the link is in the
description below. Thank you for watching
this video. If you have any questions,
please feel free to ask them in the
comments section. And don't forget to
subscribe for more live projects with me.